Abraham: Cyber security professionals are
always on the lookout for new threats and
use many different sources to find them.
By combining information from different
sources, a better picture can be seen.
Let’s look at some of
the sources they use.
Nicole: Indicators of Compromise
are pieces of forensic data that
serve as evidence of potential
intrusions on a system or network
and may be unusual traffic, unknown
files, or suspicious activity.
These enable information security
professionals and system administrators
to detect intrusion attempts.
This information can offer actionable
threat intelligence that can be shared
with the cyber security community.
Abraham: Below the surface of the
‘open web’ we all use, lies the
Deep, and Dark web and these are not
accessible by standard search engines.
This part of the internet hides someone’s
identity and location and is only
accessible through specialist browsers.
The dark web is a channel for all
kinds of illegal activities and
cyber criminals use them to purchase
hacking tools and stolen data.
Nicole: Social media platforms are
a conduit for cyber attacks as data
sharing is an inherent part of the apps.
They provide a ready resource of
personal data which is meant to be
shared between family and friends but can
instead be accessed by cyber criminals.
Privacy settings are in place, but most
users don’t give these a second glance.
Phishing is common on social media
and fake accounts are easy to set up.
Abraham: Messaging platforms are used
by threat actors to communicate as well
as finding out about data leaks etc.
Chat networks are used in a number of ways
by cyber criminals for advertising their
products and services such as cashing
out, carding and crypto currency fraud.
Nicole: Cyber attacks and cyber offensive
capabilities, are blurring the lines
between spies and malicious hackers.
Nation state and non-state actors are
reshaping the cyber threat landscape.
Threat actors can inject high levels
of geopolitical instability and
some nations use cyber espionage and
criminality as a tool, to destabilise or
gain economic or commercial advantage.
Current geopolitical tensions are
constantly monitored to offer clues of
who might be targeted in the next attack.
Abraham: Malware analysis can help to
show indicators of compromise to look for
as signs of a system breach it cand also
give an insight into the latest tactics
and techniques be used by threat actors.
Nicole: Exploit databases are archives of
public exploits and vulnerable software.
They are developed by ‘pentesters’ and
‘vulnerability researchers’ and give
insights into which exploits are available
to threat actors and which vulnerabilities
need to be prioritised for patching.
Abraham: Paste sites are sites where users
can share plain text blocks as a link.
These can be used innocently but more
often than not, are used to leak breached
data, source codes, links to dark web
sites or targets of upcoming attacks.
Nicole: Information sharing platforms
are sites that provide information
about current threat actor activities.
They may be government funded, or
independent, and include the UK
‘National Cyber Security Centre’s
Cyber Security Information Sharing
Partnership’ and the ‘Financial Services
Information Sharing and Analysis Centre’.
For more information on these and
how cyber professionals use their
services, check out the weblinks below.